༼ སྡིག་བཤགས་ཉམས་ལེན་བྱེད་ཚུལ་སྙིང་བསྡུས། ༽
Concise Practice of Confessing Misdeeds.
བདག་དང་འགྲོ་བ་ནམ་མཁའི་མཐའ་དང་མཉམ་པའི་སེམས་ཅན་ཐམས་ཅད་དུས་འདི་ནས་བཟུང་སྟེ་བྱང་ཆུབ་སྙིང་པོ་ལ་མཆིས་ཀྱི་བར་དུ་དཔལ་ལྡན་བླ་མ་དམ་པ་རྣམས་ལ་སྐྱབས་སུ་མཆིའོ། །
I and all sentient beings, as vast as space, take refuge in the glorious, holy Gurus until the essence of enlightenment.
བཅོམ་ལྡན་འདས་དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་དགྲ་བཅོམ་པ་ཡང་དག་པར་རྫོགས་པའི་སངས་རྒྱས་དཔལ་རྒྱལ་བ་ཤཱཀྱ་ཐུབ་པ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Bhagavan, Tathagata, Arhat, Perfectly Completed Buddha, the Glorious Conqueror Shakyamuni, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་རྡོ་རྗེ་སྙིང་པོས་རབ་ཏུ་འཇོམས་པ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Vajra Essence Destroyer, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་རིན་ཆེན་འོད་འཕྲོ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Jewel Radiant Light, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་ཀླུ་དབང་གི་རྒྱལ་པོ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata King, Lord of the Nagas, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་དཔའ་བོའི་སྡེ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Army of Heroes, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་དཔལ་དགྱེས་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Glorious Joy, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་རིན་ཆེན་མེ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Jewel Fire, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་རིན་ཆེན་ཟླ་འོད་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Jewel Moonlight, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་མཐོང་བ་དོན་ཡོད་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Meaningful to Behold, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་རིན་ཆེན་ཟླ་བ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Jewel Moon, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་དྲི་མ་མེད་པ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Stainless One, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་དཔལ་བྱིན་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Bestower of Glory, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་ཚངས་པ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Pure One, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་ཚངས་པས་བྱིན་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Bestowed by Purity, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་ཆུ་ལྷ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Water God, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་ཆུ་ལྷའི་ལྷ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata God of Water Gods, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་དཔལ་བཟང་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Glorious Goodness, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་ཙན་དན་དཔལ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Glorious Sandalwood, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་གཟི་བརྗིད་མཐའ་ཡས་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Endless Splendor, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་འོད་དཔལ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Glorious Light, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་མྱ་ངན་མེད་པའི་དཔལ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Glory Free of Sorrow (Ashokashri), I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་སྲེད་མེད་ཀྱི་བུ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Son of Non-Craving (Narayana), I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་མེ་ཏོག་དཔལ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Glorious Flower, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་ཚངས་པའི་འོད་ཟེར་རྣམ་པར་རོལ་པས་མངོན་པར་མཁྱེན་པ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Clearly Knowing through the Play of Brahma's Rays, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་པདྨའི་འོད་ཟེར་རྣམ་པར་རོལ་པས་མངོན་པར་མཁྱེན་པ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Clearly Knowing through the Play of the Lotus Rays, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་ནོར་དཔལ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Glorious Wealth, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་དྲན་པའི་དཔལ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Glorious Mindfulness, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་མཚན་དཔལ་ཤིན་ཏུ་ཡོངས་གྲགས་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Most Widely Renowned and Glorious Name, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་དབང་པོའི་ཏོག་གི་རྒྱལ་མཚན་གྱི་རྒྱལ་པོ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata King of the Victory Banner, Pinnacle of Power, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་ཤིན་ཏུ་རྣམ་པར་གནོན་པའི་དཔལ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Glorious and Very Brave, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་གཡུལ་ལས་རྣམ་པར་རྒྱལ་བ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Fully Victorious in Battle, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་རྣམ་པར་གནོན་པས་གཤེགས་པའི་དཔལ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Glory of the One Gone through Bravery, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་ཀུན་ནས་སྣང་བ་བཀོད་པའི་དཔལ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Glory of the Array of Universal Illumination, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་རིན་ཆེན་པདྨས་རྣམ་པར་གནོན་པ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata Brave with the Jewel Lotus, I prostrate.
དེ་བཞིན་གཤེགས་པ་དགྲ་བཅོམ་པ་ཡང་དག་པར་རྫོགས་པའི་སངས་རྒྱས་རི་དབང་གི་རྒྱལ་པོ་ལ་ཕྱག་འཚལ་ལོ། །
To the Tathagata, Arhat, Perfectly Completed Buddha, King of the Lord of Mountains, I prostrate.
བདག་གིས་ཚེ་འཁོར་བ་ཐོག་མ་མེད་པ་ནས་ད་ལྟ་ལ་ཐུག་གི་བར་དུ་ལུས་ངག་ཡིད་གསུམ་གྱིས་སྡིག་པ་མི་དགེ་བའི་ལས་ཅི་བགྱིས་པ་ཐམས་ཅད་... མཐོལ་ལོ་བཤགས་སོ། །
Whatever negative actions I have committed through body, speech, and mind from beginningless time until now... I openly declare and confess them all.
དགེ་བ་འདི་ཡིས་མྱུར་དུ་བདག་སངས་རྒྱས་བཅོམ་ལྡན་འགྲུབ་གྱུར་ནས། །འགྲོ་བ་གཅིག་ཀྱང་མ་ལུས་པ། །དེ་ཡི་ས་ལ་འགོད་པར་ཤོག །
By this merit, may I quickly attain Buddhahood and lead every single being to that state.